ANUJ GUPTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

anujguptaofficial1@gmail.com

\+91-9911392160

DELHI, INDIA

LinkedIn



Plutus Sales

anujguptal.p.s@gmail.com



Summary

I'm currently working as a Data Analyst in ElanceMart Solutions. I have completed my Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering. I like to do ordinary work in an extraordinary manner. I'm quite creative and focused on work. Regularity, dedication, and self-motivation are the key features of my life. I regularly read new research, development, and innovation by tech giants in my free time.

Professional Skills

Programming language - Java, Python, R, C/C++

Database: MySQL, PI/SQL

DSA: Data structures, algorithm analysis, DSA basics

Soft Skills: Planning & Management, Public Speaking, Handling Clients, Digital Marketing

Web development: Frontend-HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, XML

Tools: MS Visual Studio, Microsoft Office, PyCharm, LibreOffice, Spyder, Jupyter, OpenCV, Anaconda, Eclipse

Operating System: Windows, Linux, MacOS, Ubuntu

Artificial Intelligence: Machine

learning, data visualization, data

analyst, data cleansing, data pre-

processing

Work Experience

Elancemart

I worked as a Business Data Analyst here with different tools.

Business Data Analyst

07/2022 - present

GizMeek I worked as a Technical Data Analyst here with different tools.

Technical Data Analyst

01/2020 - 10/2020

I worked as a python developer & worked on ML models & datasets

Python & Machine learning

The Spark Foundation

01/2019 - 04/2019

I worked as a Strategical Analyst here under a team of interns & seniors & learnedgoogle analytics & statistical analysis

TheBrinkWire

Strategical Analyst

01/2022 - 06/2022

I worked as a Technical Content Writer here for regular articles and publications for the tech world.

MasticateByte

Technical Content Writer

06/2018 - 12/2018

Work Experience

Advanced Level
Telecommunication Training
Centre (ALTTC)

Intern 06/2019 - 07/2019 Worked on handling hardware components of Embedded systems. Writing VHDLcodes to run hardware.

Education

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology

2017 - 2021

GGSIPU B. Tech- Electronic and Communication Engineer (ECE) 74%

The Baptist Convent School

- 2017

CBSE Class -12th (76%) in PCM with PE2016

The Baptist Convent School

- 2015

CBSE Class -10th (92%) in PCM with PE2014

Projects

Dual Halo Triple Material

2020 - 2021

The analytical subthreshold current model of Dual Halo Triple Material Surrounding gate MOSFET and comparisons to other triple materialMOSFETs

MOSFETs

MOSFETs - Designing and analysis of dual-halo triple material surrounding gate 2020

- 2020

Chronic Kidney Disease

It's a Machine Learning-based predictive analysis of patients. The worked for it.

2019 - 2020

CRICINFO - Cricket Data on Demand

2018 - 2019

This project uses Python to web scrape the data that we provide from EspnCricketinfo. The aim to store data for a particular match using the unique match number embedded in the matching URL from ESPNCricketinfo, respectively, and database daily for recent games and provide data for the matches not stored in our databases by gathering the data on the go.

Attendance Management System

2017 - 2018

2020

An attendance management system refers to an organization's approach to tracking employee time and attendance information. An accurate attendance and time tracking system helps you save time and effort in calculating your employees' working hours.

Certifications

Machine learning & Data Science from IIT Delhi

2023	Python, Machine Learning, Data Science, Artificial Intelligence from NIELIT, Future Skills
2022	Strategical Analyst at TheBrinkWire, Technical Content Writer at Masticatebyte
2021	Case Studies on Healthcare Industry, Sales and Marketing, Insurance Industry, HR from Great Learning

2020	Web development Front-end from Udemy	
2020	Professional Python, C, C++ & Core-Java, Advance Java Course from NPTEL,Udemy, Sololearn & NIELIT	
2018	Tech content writer & analysis at GizMeek	

Research - Publication

IJRASET: MOSFETs (MOSFETs)

I worked on a research paper on MOSFETs - Designing and analysis of dual-halo triple material surrounding gate

Languages

Hindi (Native) | English (Professional Proficiency) | French (Beginners) | Punjabi (Beginners)

Interests

- CrossFit games
- Trekking
- Sports activities, travelingListening
- music
- I regularly used to solve puzzles, Reasoning, Real life & Critical problems. I like
- to play Badminton, Volleyball, Chess & PS/PC games.

Achievements

- French certified in school
- Hackerrank: 2-star coder
- Project Euler: Top 500 in India
- 3rd position in Badminton at Regional level in school
- IBM Bluemix hackathon IIIT-D 2018
- Roblox Junior Hackathon Koding Kingdom 2020
- Rajasthan Digifest Hackathon 2018
- Best Well-Dressed Award in School
- Best Book review award in library
- Class representative (CR) for 2 years
- Elected as Class Monitor (CM) for 3 years in school
- SIH (Smart India Hackathon) 2018 Level-1: Shortest route/path algorithm for traveling of users

References

- Cognizant: Prateek Gupta: SWE Full Stack Engineer
- Cadence: Lakshay Gupta: Software Engineer I (SDE-I)